what up scobie's all right we got
exciting stuff today check out what I
got right here some ultra rare merch but
I promise this is not a merge scope II
no more mirja scobie's I lost my voice
Oh screaming a lot in Vegas we're not
talking about drive that I I I'm talking
about you don't even shout him out bro
oh yeah I got a haircut I got a shave -
look I shaved I got some mapping stuff
today yeah what's up
I'll even try it we'll try it on a user
route - so I show you that this isn't
just let's see if RC Richmond
comes back I'll tell them on scope now
so first I'll try it on one of mine
so this is what it looks like while it's
running takes a little bit it's got a
boot up here got a filter out all the
crap yeah there we go
now wait hang on it's just kind of
reinitialize if just fast-forward a bit
alright now we're initialized let's map
so I'll move this guy out of the way
here and now we're making a map I'm
gonna turn you guys there we go you can
see that this is a map this is done
using sensor fusion this is a great
panda route I just disable these we
don't need that look at the lanes look
at the quality of that stuff here guys
could the quality of those lanes being
recovered stuff precise to ten
centimeters okay so I've actually
already made this map and now let me
show you what it looks like when you
real oka lies in the map so when you're
like figuring out okay where is the
picture with respect to the map and I'll
show you what it looks like now remember
this is all in world frame coordinates
so we actually have all of these points
every single one of these little points
we have in full ecef coordinates so
let's take a look at this I think this
is gonna be pretty cool look at that
guy's
that's the precision to which we're
covering the lanes in the world 10
centimeters that's what's gonna be used
to train the newest models coming out in
the next open violet look at that
precision guys look at it boom
yo I love shipping you know I love
shipping I let's try it on another one
we're gonna have to do a little
processing on it remember this is live I
haven't actually tested any of this so
who knows if anyone's gonna work but
yeah so if RC Wriston gets back to me
it's sad to be a rout we'll try it on a
user-contributed round as well yeah so
that's that I have others that I've
already made the map for mapping takes a
bit of time mapping takes about about
five minutes for a minute but the good
news is who cares just buy more
computers because computers are so cheap
y'all alright see where else we got
let's go over here - we also said we
also have the 26th minute of this
process so let's take a look here you
have to do a little bit of running
alright using the vision data we're
filtering this all together in a
beautiful unified architecture look look
look that's not coming along guys
alright processing process process
process
yeah we don't need more machines by all
the machines we want from the cloud
right then it processes gotta save all
the stuff to disk it saves all this
debug information to desk oh yeah look
at that look at that turn yo is that
model gonna be precise or what
that's localizing itself in the map now
we'll wobble that won't nothing using
the flat world hypothesis look at that
precision s amazing y'all finally are
getting some good results with napping
and I swear I'd never tried this I've
never tried this section before that
just localized us in the map look at how
it's seeing the lane right through that
car beautiful yeah look man don't
believe the hype how about over
correction what over correction I didn't
see any over correction loser over
correction it's common using this so we
know what you have a new model yet we're
working on it okay we have it we have a
route right here
unfortunately it takes so long hang on
let's just let's just take a look at one
more of mine oh we using the cloud we're
using the cloud for parts of it the new
ml guys pretty good let's just look at
this one that's almost finished I will
try it on use it around quickly too
so remember what this is doing right now
is localizing us in the map so this
stuff will also all run at test time as
well so all the Aeons will be able if
you guys saw that we shipped orb D in
the last release using those features
will be able to put every eon live into
a map with this sort of precision yeah
take a look at that oh that's pretty
good
don't know a little bit more it could be
more precise I don't know we're gonna be
you're gonna far exceed supercruise yeah
we're making point cloud maps of the
whole world we're gonna we're gonna give
parts of it away for free we're gonna
give where all the lanes are in the
world away completely free our HD Maps
like equivalent to what all the other
companies are making is HD Maps we're
just gonna give them away for free I
don't care
I just love winning me a user
you give me times in the real world time
now to use that what minute is good okay
well if it starts at 48 then try it on
some side girls let's try us inside us
I don't know what we're gonna get all
right guys
we running a user route right here this
route is user-contributed with a grey
panda no voice I mean no voice you get
you guys sometimes say you can't hear me
I think that's a lie
yeah I knew that was a lie all right so
we've got a run sad net cuz we got to
filter out the cars the problem of cars
they don't move like the rest of the
scene so this stuff is also all hacked
up to kind of be single threaded so it
runs nicely on cloud machines all right
wall frames here notice possible
overexposure auntie cam yeah I know I
got to redo the exposure oh I was like
halfway doing it but I have date luck
that night I went out and then I didn't
finish fixing expose around the driver
camera I don't have to do that next
release y'all next release oh you guys
know what Eyring we're trying to hire
someone to come in full time to work on
the driver monitoring stuff so if you
know anyone got any smart friends tell
them give me a job and comment on any I
the car properties I like that important
you just called them in let's see we got
here yeah that's fine
not always crash is the first time
because the best a little GDK gtk is
broken
all right cool all right I don't issue
lies fast RC risk man here's your route
being mapped right here
you snap it and created this guy it's
hard to hit the keys here's your map you
create it right here tell the people in
slack tell I'm not lying
give a great panda you have any yawn we
can make maps out of your stuff look at
the lane lines you can see them all
there ho-jon as far doesn't display time
i'm not support man you know support
come hey i definitely you're out there
you go
notice how the cars have all been
filtered out let's thanks to you guys
with comic colouring the driver video
challenge we've gotten very few
submissions no good ones yet I don't
think it's that hard we've one candidate
who came in in person who I'm excited
about hopefully I'll do a good job but
yeah so we're at Frank 861 so
unfortunately mapping takes forever yeah
I mean this is all part of the pipeline
so we can just enable this in the cloud
how I was hacking supercruise you know
Ricardo he's on vacation this week so
there's no super cruise hacking can you
map the route without lane markings
absolutely we just it doesn't matter you
got have a great panda though if you
have a great panda because you need a
great panda to avoid scale draft um
Opie drive while training maps yeah
that's fine here's why we make maps but
yeah this stuff is really all starting
to work we'll see how long I hang out
with you guys if I hang out with you
guys long enough we can actually look at
the lanes we can relocate math looks
pretty cool right do it yeah we'll see a
long hang out so this is a visualizer
from warp slang
we've hacked in all our own sensors to
it as well
some people might say oh why do you show
this all off because guys Eli was
talking about I'm so happy when he talks
like this um this isn't like this isn't
a secret what we're doing here none of
this is secrets but if you try to
compete with us you'll find that we are
just doing it better than you like other
companies are all trying to work on the
same problem as well and you know it
took us a bit you guys have watched the
other mapping periscopes and you've seen
how it's been how it's been worse and
now it's starting to get better oh so
that was finally done listen we're at
frame 384 so we got another 400 to go we
could track farm roads maybe on the next
one
but yeah I mean there's no there's no
secret in the idea there's only secrets
in the execution the secrets and how
we've actually wired all this stuff look
at those lanes guys look at that look at
that precision and these are all the all
these points are globally accurate so
these aren't some points and some
relative space these are in global ecef
space do we use lanes to calculate we
use lengths to calculate where you are
and then we know where to draw okay no
no no guys look if you want like open
but look here's the thing about open
palette all right so first off you're a
bottom and open pilot is beta is alpha
software we're not like looking to add
this is maybe why I get overly
frustrated when people ask for features
like we're not looking to add features
this is not a consumer product we're not
looking to build a consumer experience
if you want it to do whatever like
suspend on blinker
whatever it's open source that stuff is
well within the realm of somebody to add
with an hour of hacking if you want to
yeah so we record the beginning and end
of all the lane lines perfectly in our
map we actually record all these 3d
points in our map
so every single point you see here
actually has a point in the world so
let's save the map it's gonna put the
map in the database all right
saving the map and then that's gonna
finish out once that's done takes a
little bit the maps are kind of big
because you see all the points they have
and the stuff is horrendously slow
because it uses like JSON and crap okay
so that's yeah you don't want features
just drive in the middle and we're good
you know we're again it's gonna be
better the lateral control is gonna get
better better is not a feature what do
we do when someone goes through the same
route again yes we go into the maps and
it'll it'll that'll get better with time
how bigger the map specifically alright
so now we got a download that GPS chip
from NASA let's post process all the GPS
to make sure that this stuff is all
actually correct within the world to ten
centimeters not just locally correct to
ten centimeters what was your question
before that yeah grab that from
NASA what are the difference in the
retina black the residents visible right
now the red is what's visible from the
current frame okay so now we're
reprocessing dual grape and of RTK it's
not necessary
you just download all this stuff from
NASA and it's pretty good the common
base stations are kind of on hold okay
so oh we got to process that oh that's
gonna take forever
hey fix that bug guys I can fix this bug
up fast it's not a bug it just processes
too much stuff when we don't actually
need to process all that so that's in
test so Sam from all from route cameras
that we don't need all from let's try
that
oh yeah there we go
oh look at that so this is good stuff
that we can then go train on as soon as
we're ready
look at that precision guys look at that
precision that's all three dimensionally
accurate it's cached lovely
it's totally guessed locally I just have
many Maps on this computer we catch all
the NASA data look at that precision
boom yeah I see your ping pong don't
worry we'll fix it cool guys let's watch
it one more time this is a user route
that I didn't know about before this
periscope started this actually works on
all the routes now pretty much I think I
think we're down to like maybe a 10%
failure right and of course you're
training them all you don't actually get
to work on all of them that's now added
to our completely global map next time
next time we'll do it downtown it's
actually easier Drive integrated 3d map
with open pilot working already yes it
already completely works I just hold it
back from you guys cuz I'm cruel and
evil oh no time for the same we have
canonicalize errs there's some key ways
to do it maybe I'll talk about it
sometime alright guys I hope you
the first successful mapping periscope
everything worked we put a user route in
you can see the top of the board they're
going to be better than supercruise how
do we plan on processing all the world
using lots of come six copies thanks for
watching make sure to buy shop
comment that a you know where it is
right I'm right with the most lip
self-driving car team on Twitter make
sure to follow us at comma AI if you're
asking every time someone asks for the
ETA for something we push the debate out
one day we push it out one day so if you
ask 7 times the 7 days late we actually
already have it all incredible we just
keep it secret no that's a lie but make
sure to borrow a chit shop.com by follow
us on Twitter , underscore hey I watch
out for fake news it's a lot of fake
news out there
props to way mo by the way for releasing
that video of the crash
totally totally not way most vaults I'm
a car literally jumped across the median
and hit them so always good to see
people being transparent and open that's
what we love to see thank you for
joining